Hello everyone and welcome to this lesson on deep learning with PyTorch.
大家好 欢迎学习这节关于用 PyTorch 进行深度学习的课程
So, here I've built a bunch of Jupyter Notebooks that will lead you
我构建了大量 Jupyter Notebook
through actually writing the code to implement deep learning networks and Python.
指导大家编写实现深度学习网络的 Python 代码
So, here we're using the PyTorch framework which
我们将使用 PyTorch 框架
is somewhat newer than TensorFlow and Keras.
它比 TensorFlow 和 Keras 更新
It's being developed by the Facebook AI research team, and completely open-source.
是由 Facebook AI 研究团队开发的 完全开源
And the reason that we've chosen PyTorch over TensorFlow and Keras is that
我们选择 PyTorch 而不是 TensorFlow 和 Keras 的原因是
it's actually more coherent with Python itself like in the way you program in Python,
它与 Python 本身更相关 就像 Python 编程一样
but also with the concepts of deep learning.
而且涉及了深度学习概念
So you'll see as you work through these notebooks,
当你完成这些 notebook 时会发现
that the concepts that you've learned about deep learning
你学习的反向传播等深度学习概念
like backpropagation are actually very natural in PyTorch,
在 PyTorch 中显得非常自然
whereas with TensorFlow and Keras,
而在 TensorFlow 和 Keras 中
you tend to have to write your code in a weird way that doesn't
编写代码的方式很奇怪
actually match the conceptual mapping of deep learning.
与深度学习的概念结构不太相符
You can also buy these notebooks in the classroom,
你可以在课堂上找到这些 notebook
in a workspace below the videos.
位于视频下方的 workspace 中
And you can download the notebooks from
还可以从 GitHub 下载这些 notebook
GitHub if you'd like to work on them on your own computer.
并在你自己的计算机上完成这些 notebook
Before we get into the actual code itself,
在查看实际代码之前
there's one thing you need to understand, tensors.
你需要理解一个概念 张量
So, tensors are basically a generalization of vectors and matrices.
张量是向量和矩阵的泛化
So, for instance, a vector is a 1-dimensional tensor.
例如 向量是一维张量
So, basically, you just have this kind of line of values.
有一行值
A matrix is a 2-dimensional tensor,
矩阵是二维张量
where you have this rectangle.
是一个长方形
So you have rows, and you have columns.
有行和列
So, basically, it's these numbers that are arrayed in
这些数字排列在二维空间中
a 2-dimensional space because we have like an x-coordinate and we have a y-coordinate.
我们有 x 坐标和 y 坐标
And then something like a color image is a 3-dimensional tensor.
彩色图像是三维张量
So, if you remember about color images,
对于彩色图像
like for every pixel,
每个像素
you can denote it with an x and a y,
都可以用 x 和 y 表示
but it also has a red,
但是它还有
green, and a blue component.
红绿蓝分量
And so, these tensors are kind of main data structure that you'll be using in PyTorch.
张量是你将在 PyTorch 中使用的主要数据结构
They helps a lot if you're able to kind of visualize them
当你使用张量时 如果能够在脑中想象出它们的结构
in your mind as you're working with them because you'll be doing a lot of things,
则对理解很有帮助 你将对它们执行很多操作
where you're looking at shapes and linear algebra operations on them.
例如查看形状 进行线性代数运算
So, it is just good to understand what these are and then
因此 有必要了解张量是什么
how they're actually kind of flowing through your network.
它们是如何穿过网络的
So, now we can actually start looking at how you use PyTorch to build neural networks.
我们可以开始学习如何使用 PyTorch 构建神经网络了
First though, I want you to understand how you actually work with tensors in PyTorch.
但是首先要讲解下如何在 PyTorch 中处理张量
I was saying tensors are the basic data structure in PyTorch.
我提到张量是 PyTorch 中的基本数据结构
So, to build your neural networks,
要构建神经网络
a lot of times you're going to be working with these tensors.
很多时候都需要处理张量
And so, it's a good idea to actually understand how they work,
因此有必要理解张量的工作原理
and your gain is conceptual understanding of them.
从概念上理解它们
So, first things first,
首先
going to import Numpy and PyTorch.
导入 NumPy 和 PyTorch
So, import torch to use your PyTorch modules.
导入 torch 以使用 PyTorch 模块
So, first off, I'm just going to create a random tensor.
首先我将创建一个随机张量
And we see, we just had these random numbers, and is 3 by 2.
可以看到这些随机数字 大小是 3x2
And then we can print other one, the same size.
然后输出另一个随机张量 大小一样
So, to get the size of a tensor, you just do x.size.
要获得张量的大小 使用 x.size
And so, this will give us a 3 by 2 as a size.
这行代码会输出大小为 3 x 2 的张量
And this will create a array of
创建一个二维张量数组
a 2-dimensional tensor of all ones with the same size as x.
值全为 1 大小和 x 相同
Then we can add these together.
然后我们可以将二者相加
And this is pretty much what you should be used to using Numpy.
基本上和 NumPy 的一样
So, in a lot of ways, using PyTorch is very similar to Numpy,
在很多方面 PyTorch 使用起来和 NumPy 都非常相似
which makes the learning curve very nice,
使学习过程变得轻松简单
because if you have experienced Numpy,
因为如果你有 NumPy 经验
then using PyTorch becomes very natural.
那么 PyTorch 用起来将很简单
So, for instance, you can index your tensors,
例如 你可以对张量使用索引
so get out the first row,
这样会获得第一行
and you can use slices.
还可以使用切片
So, if you want all the rows for the second column, it will do that.
如果你想要第二列的所有行 可以这么操作
You see now tensors in PyTorch have two forms of methods.
PyTorch 中的张量有两种形式的方法
So, one form creates a new tensor. So, z.add.
一种形式是创建新的张量
So this just adds the number 1 to our tensor z.
z.add 使张量 z 加 1
This gives us this. And what this does is it creates a new tensor.
得出这个结果 它会创建一个新的张量
So, basically, a copy of z and then add one to it.
创建一个 z 的副本并使其加 1
And just to check, okay. So this is the old tensor,
检查下 没错 这是之前的张量
and this is the new tensor that was made.
这是新建的张量
However, pretty much all the methods on these tensors also have an in-place version.
但是 关于张量的几乎所有方法都存在原地版本
So, what that means is that if we add one again,
意思是 如果我们再加 1
then it looks like we get a new tensor,
似乎创建了新的张量
but it's actually changed our tensor.
但实际上更改了张量
So, what it means in-place is it changes
原地操作是指
the values in the memory like for the memory of this tensor.
更改了内存中的值 更改了此张量的内存
So, without an underscore, it creates a new tensor.
没有下划线的话 创建一个新的张量
And with its underscore,
有下划线的话
it does the operation in-place.
执行原地操作
And so, you keep the same tensor.
保持相同的张量
It just changes the values in memory that a tensor is pointing to.
但是更改了该张量在内存中指向的值
So, something you'll be doing really often with PyTorch is looking at
你在 PyTorch 中经常会执行的操作是
the size and shape of your tensors and then reshaping your tensors.
查看张量的大小和形状 然后调整张量的形状
So, again, to just check out the size or the shape of one of your tensors,
要检查张量的大小或形状
you just do.size, and this tells you that it's a 3 by 2 tensor.
使用 do.size 结果显示是 3 x 2 张量
And say, we want to resize it to make it 2 by 3.
假设我们想将形状调整为 2 x 3
So, it's still z.resize_(2,3).
输入 z.resize_(2,3)
So you'll notice that we have an underscore here,
你会注意到 这里有个下划线
which means that this method,
表明这个方法
this reshaping is done in place.
是原地调整形状
So if you look at z again,
再次查看 z 会发现
then it is now a 2 by 3 matrix,
现在是一个 2 x 3 矩阵
when originally it was a 3 by 2 matrix.
原来是 3 x 2 矩阵
Finally, one of my favorite features of PyTorch is that it's really
最后 我最喜欢的 PyTorch 功能之一是
easy to convert from a Numpy array into a Torch tensor.
可以轻松地从 NumPy 数组转换为 Torch 张量
So this makes it really,
这样的话
really nice when you're working with data,
处理数据将非常非常轻松
because most of the time,
因为大部分时间
you're preprocessing, and things like that are going to be done in Numpy.
你都是预处理数据 这些操作可以在 NumPy 中完成
And then you'll build your network at a PyTorch.
然后在 PyTorch 中构建网络
And then you'll put that back in a Numpy to do like the rest of your analysis are,
然后再回到 NumPy 中完成剩余分析步骤
or creating figures, or
或创建图形
whatever kind of connected up to the rest of your program with Numpy.
或使用 NumPy 完成程序的剩余步骤
So, first, I'm just going to create a random array with Numpy.
首先 我将使用 NumPy 创建一个随机数组
Random 4 by 3 array looks like that.
随机 4 x 3 数组 看起来这样
And so, to change this array into a Torch tensor,
要将此数组转换为 Torch 张量
you say from_numpy and you pass the array.
输入 from_numpy 然后传入该数组
And that gives us a Torch tensor with the same values.
这样就会获得具有相同值的 PyTorch 张量
And then, if we want to take a PyTorch tensor,
如果想要将 PyTorch 张量
and we want to change it to a Numpy array,
变成 NumPy 数组
you say b, which gives a tensor,.numpy.
输入 b 它是一个张量 然后输入 .numpy
So, the Numpy method will return you a Numpy array.
numpy 方法将返回一个 NumPy 数组
So, one thing to know, when you take a Numpy array and you change it to a tensor,
注意 当你将 NumPy 数组变成张量时
the Numpy array and the tensor, they share memory.
NumPy 数组和张量共享内存
So what this means is that if you change values for your tensor in-place,
这意味着 如果原地更改张量的值
it's also going to change the values of your Numpy array.
也会更改 NumPy 数组的值
So, for instance, if we multiply in-place by two, we get that.
例如 我们原地乘以 2 得出这个结果
And then if we look back at our Numpy array, it's also changed.
再回来看看 NumPy 数组 它也变了
So, just something to be aware of as you're using this,
在使用该方法时 需要注意的是
that if you are linking your Torch tensors and your Numpy arrays,
如果你要将 PyTorch 张量与 NumPy 数组相关联
that they're going to be sharing the same memory.
它们将共享相同的内存
So, just something to look out for,
这一点要注意
so you don't cause yourself bugs.
防止造成 bug
I'll see you next video. Cheers.
下个视频见 加油